Manojit Nath | Cybersecurity Consultant

+91-844-742-2285 | manojitnath28@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/manojitnath | New Delhi

Profile

Cybersecurity Consultant with experience and expertise in cyber risk management & strategy, and implementing cybersecurity solutions that drives business growth and improves information systems. Domain expertise in Cloud Security, IT/OT Risk Management, ISO 27001 Audit.

Experience

Cybersecurity Consultant | Deloitte (Dec 2018 - Present)

- Prepare OT Security monitoring solution proposals, SOW, & Network Segmentation guidelines as per Purdue Model Network Architecture
- Develop OT Security firewall standard & guidelines, & perform third party OT gap assessment
- Developed assessment plan for newly implemented IAM solutions (SailPoint), and its integration with other existing platforms (such as CyberArk, SuccessFactors)
- Perform Risk assessment by leveraging the NIST CSF and assess the cyber security service maturity level
- Performed general IT controls testing over user access management, change management

Information Security Analyst | Mahindra SSG (Oct 2016 – Oct 2018)

- Performed Information Security 27001 Internal audit at a multinational car manufacturing corporation, assessing systems/network availability, security, and data integrity to identify, manage, and reduce risks and ensure general compliance.
- Performed Information Security Internal audit at multiple locations for an Indian automobile client to identify IT related risks. Areas include networks, operating systems, ERP, databases, security, and disaster recovery.
- Implemented ISMS and conducted Risk Assessment for one of the top Dairy Producer.
- Prepared audit reports for distribution to management and senior management documenting the results of the audit.
- Provide end user training to employees after the successful implementation of ISMS.
- Prepared IT Audit checklist in alignment with Compliance Matrix of Guidelines for Indian Government Websites.

IT Analyst | Suntec Services (Apr 2015 – Oct 2016)

- Record, generate report and implement change control procedure.
- Generate weekly change control reports for management review.
- Performing System Audit on a monthly basis to ensure endpoints have controls as defined in the ISO 27001 ISMS Policies and Procedures.
- Review Patch Management, Antivirus, and Privilege Account Access.
- Review & identify improvements of network security controls related to appropriate internet usage in line with the IT Policy & Procedures.
- Responsible for adherence and implementation of ISMS policies and procedures for IT department under IT Manager related to the following domains:
 - Change Management

- Antivirus Management
- Acceptable Usage Policy
- Network Security Policy
- Backup Policy
- Restoration Policy

Professional Affiliations

• ISO 27001 Lead Auditor Certification

Education

B.Tech - Electronics and Communication Engineering

Swami Vivekananda Institute of Engineering & Technology - 2013